JACOPO PRADA

Web Developer

Profile

I am a London-based web developer with an academic and professional background in strategy and marketing. After graduating and working on the business side of things for startups and agencies, I joined General Assembly's Web Development Immersive bootcamp in 2015, learning the key concepts of programming while building full-stack web applications. For the past two years I have been developing websites and mobile apps for a digital agency, working on a variety of technologies on the client and server side. I am now seeking a new web development position that would allow me to expand my knowledge and explore new technologies, starting from January 2018.

Contact

jac@tortugalabs.io www.jacprada.com linkedin.com/in/jacprada

Current Occupation

Full Stack Web Developer

We Are Telescopic: Jan 2016-now

We Are Telescopic is a team of experts in development and digital strategy specialised in membership websites, e-commerce shops and mobile apps. **Areas of Responsibility:** Front and Back-End Development, Strategy, UX.

White Collar Factory - whitecollarfactory.com

AngularJS, Sass, Animations, SVGs

White Collar Factory is content-rich website based on an asymmetrical and flexible grid system. Being responsible for the front-end development of the site, I have worked on an extensive range of tasks, including the custom zoom and map-based functionality as well as a series of transitions and animations that have been optimised for all main browsers and devices.

Kinfolk - kinfolk.com

PHP, WordPress, WooCommerce

Our team was responsible for implementing the back-end functionality of the new Kinfolk website and e-commerce shop. The project gave me the opportunity to experience PHP at a more advanced level by developing a custom paywall for the online magazine as well as tweaking and extending the default WooCommerce online store functionality.

Mission Saigon - missionsaigon.com

PHP, Wordpress, jQuery, Velocity, Sass, Animations, SVGs

I had the opportunity to work individually on the website for a new restaurant in Paris, being responsible for both back-end and front-end functionality of the site. Given the limited scope of the project, I maximised my efforts on a series of front-end tweaks to deliver a pleasant and smooth user experience.

GOSH Global - itunes.apple.com/gb/app/gosh-global/id1072124013

Swift, Xcode, User Interface

After having developed a number of hybrid mobile apps using Ionic and AngularJS, I approached native iOS app development through the GOSH medical app. While the functionality of the app is simple, building its Arabic interface and working in a new environment had posed real challenges.

Tech Interests

Front-end



I feel confident in building responsive sites and web apps in HTML/CSS and JavaScript, which is my primary working language. I am very passionate about JavaScript and I would like to broaden my knowledge in the fields of ES6/ES7/ES8 and of front-end framworks such as Vue.js and React.

Back-end



Despite not being my main area of expertise, I enjoy getting involved with back-end development. My language of choice is PHP, but I have some experience with Ruby on Rails as well as Node.js and I am always keen on learning new languages and frameworks.

Mobile Apps



I have developed a series of hybrid mobile applications using Ionic and AngularJS.
I also have some limited experience with native iOS development, which I hope to do more in the future as I particularly enjoyed working with Xcode and Swift.

Professional Experience

Maker

Tortuga Labs: Jun 2015-now

Tortuga Labs is the brand I have created to sign the projects that I carry out during my free time. These personal projects and collaborations give me the opportunity to improve my skills and learn new ones while having fun. **Areas of Responsibility:** Web Development, Digital Strategy, UX/UI Design.

Teaching Assistant

General Assembly: Sep 2015-Dec 2015

General Assembly is an innovative educational institution and a global community of developers, designers and business nerds.

Areas of Responsibility: Back and Front-End Development, Code Review.

Digital Strategist

Blend Creative Agency: Jan 2014-May 2015

Blend is a fast-growing creative boutique that delivers an ecosystem of digital services ecompassing the entire branding process.

Areas of Responsibility: Digital Strategy, Business Consulting, Branding.

Business Development Intern

Soply: Sep 2013-Dec 2013

Formerly known as PhotoPitch, Soply is a startup that provides tailored visual content for brands crowdsourced from creatives worldwide. **Areas of Responsibility:** Business Development, Marketing Strategy and Social Media Management.

Digital Media Intern

Imille Digital Agency: Mar 2012-Jun 2012

Imille is a mid-sized agency that explores innovative branding solutions and creates integrated communication strategies for the digital era.

Areas of Responsibility: Digital Strategy, SEO, Copywriting.

Education

Web Development Immersive

General Assembly - London: 2015

Intensive full-time three-month programming bootcamp.

M.Sc. Strategic Market Creation

Copenhagen Business School - Copenhagen: 2012-2014

Master of Science degree that takes a market-oriented approach to entrepreneurship and innovation, focusing on the role that marketing, brand management, product development as well as business model innovation play in the creation of new opportunities for a company.

Exchange Program

University of Melbourne - Melbourne: 2010

Exchange semester staying at the Newman residential college.

B.Sc. Management of Arts, Culture and Communication

Bocconi University - Milan: 2008-2011

Bachelor of Science degree that combines rigorous courses in economics and management applied to the context of arts, cultural industries and communication.

Other Interests

Urban Photography



I have been taking photos with analogue cameras since 2010. I mainly focus on urban landscape shots using a variety of old Russian and toy cameras.

Good Music



I worked as a music journalist for webzines and magazines during high-school times. I listen to all kinds of records made with passion, but I have a soft spot for ambient sounds and electronic beats.

Mountain Life



I was born and raised in the Dolomites UNESCO World Heritage Site. When I am at home, I spend the winter on ski slopes and hike with my family during the summer.

Adventure Travel



I always try to visitnew exciting destinations whenever I can.
Last year I travelled around Iceland in a van and visited North Korea. This summer I hiked in the Slovenian Alps and I just got back from Japan.

Animal World



I have been vegetarian for the past ten years, I am a proud supporter of the Guide Dogs for the Blind association and I co-own a lovely German Shepherd named Elly.